Okay, in this video we're going to be
covering activities, project activities.
And there are a couple of different ways
of creating activities based on whether
it's a predictive life cycle or an agile
life cycle.
So let's talk about the predictive first,
predictive life cycle first.
Now, in a predictive environment,
remember the basic breakdown, right,
the basic progressive
elaboration, if you like, is you take
your project and then you
decompose it into work packages.
So this is what we talked about in the
scope management section when we were
talking about the work breakdown
structure.
You create the work breakdown structure
first, right?
So the weight breakdown
structure is decomposing
your project down to the work package.
That is scope management.
In this section though, in this knowledge
area, which is the schedule, schedule
management, we're taking this a step
further, in which case we're taking each
individual work package and then further
decomposing it into individual activities.
So each work package then is broken down
into individual activities.
And remember the tooling technique is
decomposition.
So the tooling technique in create work
breakdown structure, right, tooling
technique in the scope management was
decomposition.
Also here in schedule management as well,
you're taking each work package and
further breaking it down, further
decomposing it into individual activity.
Now, also as a review,
remember, activities
are not part of the work
breakdown structure.
The lowest level of the WBS is the work
package.
If you ever see that in a question,
the lowest level is a work package.
So activities officially are not part of
the work package.
So it's a separate document altogether,
separate artifact altogether, separate
process altogether of taking each work
package and further decomposing it into
individual activities okay so let's look
at this in a bit more detail so on my next
slide here I have the work breakdown
structure example that we had in the
previous video right now one of the
previous videos so here we have the
kitchen remodeling project we're breaking
it down to appliances countertops cabinets
flooring there's all the work that needs
to be done, then we're further breaking it
down, like the appliances, we need old
apply, we can keep one of the old
appliances like the microwave,
and we need some new
appliances like refrigerator
oven and dishwasher.
So the lowest level of the work breakdown
structure is the work package.
Now, this is the WBS.
Now, for each work package,
we're going to further break
that down, further decompose
that into individual activities.
So let's just take one of in this case the
refrigerator.
So on the next slide here,
we're further decomposing the
refrigerator, the work package
refrigerator, into activities.
And what would be the activities for the
refrigerator?
Things like select the refrigerator,
order the refrigerator, deliver it,
install the fridge, and then finally test
the installation of the refrigerator.
So these would be the activities related
to the work package called refrigerator.
Now notice, this box down here, notice
the use of verbs to describe activities.
That is what distinguishes an activity
from a work package.
Verbs, action words, right?
Select refrigerator, order refrigerator,
deliver refrigerator.
These are all action works.
These are all verbs, something that you
do, some action that you take.
Whereas a work package, just a noun.
Just refrigerator.
This is what we are delivering.
But what are all the steps required to
deliver this refrigerator?
These are all the steps involved.
And that's how you distinguish a work
package from an activity.
Okay, now, what we just talked about was a
predictive.
In an agile environment, remember,
the breakdown is slightly different.
The decomposition is slightly different.
You have user stories.
And user stories are broken down into
individual activities.
However, you start off with a high-level
user story.
A high-level user story, just like
high-level requirements, right?
You're in a predictive, you
have a high-level requirement,
you're further breaking it
down into detail requirements.
Same thing here in an agile environment.
You have high-level user stories.
A high-level user story
is known as an epic,
very large user story, very high-level.
This is broken down, right?
An epic is broken down into features,
and features then will also contain
capabilities but several features make up
an epic now features then are further
broken down into individual user stories
and a user story is a functionality right
the functionality that adds value to to
the customer right and it meets this
criteria of invest which we'll talk about
in the in the next slide and then each
user story then is further
broken down further
decomposed into individual
tasks or activities Okay.
Now, let's talk about this acronym now,
invest, right, on this next slide here.
So a user story has to meet this acronym,
if you like, it has to meet this criteria,
right?
And basically the old saying is, you need
to invest in good user stories, right?
And invest stands for independent,
negotiable, valuable, estimable,
size, which has to be small, right,
and testable.
So a user story then, remember,
it needs to be broken down, right?
You have a high-level user story,
you're further breaking it down,
well, how do we know we've broken it down
enough, enough to create our activities?
Well, we know we've
broken it down enough if it's
independent, independent
of other user stories.
So it's not one user story is dependent on
another user story, right?
We can't have all these complex
dependencies, so we need to break it down.
So there isn't a lot of dependencies
between one and the other.
And therefore, it can be prioritized a lot
easier.
right negotiable right a user story is not
a contract you know more of a discussion
more of a conversation remember what we're
trying to do we're trying to add value
we're trying to add value to the customer
right so you know customer collaboration
instead of contract negotiation right so
or rather over not instead of customer
collaboration over
contract negotiation right
so we're not trying to
create a contract, right?
I mean, a user story, it has to be agreed
to.
It has to be more of a discussion,
more of a conversation.
Also, valuable, right?
So it is going to actually provide some
kind of business value to the customer.
And estimable.
It has to be small enough so that team
members can actually prioritize.
They can estimate the level of effort.
So it has to be small enough so we can
estimate the level of effort.
And that goes to the next acronym or next
part of the acronym
S, right, which is size.
It has to be small enough.
It has to be small enough so we can break
it into individual activities.
It has to be small enough so it can be
prioritized.
And so it's, and it is independent of
other user stories.
And it can be small enough
so we can estimate the
relative size and it can
meet our definition of done.
We can identify the definition of done.
And again, we defined what the definition
of done was in an early video and then
testable right it's small enough so that
we can test it and ensure it meets this
definition of done so these are a couple
of different approaches then right to
creating the activities based on whether
it's a predictive or whether it's an agile